Nyrell Leonor

Seattle, WA I (206) 661-2450 I nyrell.leonor2000@gmail.com I www.nyrellcl.com I Github I LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Front-end Developer skilled in creating intuitive, responsive websites and applications using HTML, SASS, and JavaScript/TypeScript, as well as libraries & frameworks such as React and Next.js. Personal experience in branding and have developed my own personal brand through various social media platforms, where I share my personal projects and insights on the latest trends and techniques in front-end development and design.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- Front-End Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, SCSS/SASS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Visual Studio Code, Vite
- Back-End Technologies: Express.js, Node.js, REST API Architecture, HTTP Requests
- **Design Principles:** User Experience (UX) Design, User Interface (UI) Design, System Design, Responsive Web Design, Mobile-first design approach.
- Frameworks & Libraries: React.js, Next.js, TailwindCSS.
- Version Control: Git

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

REST API Development - TypeScript, REST Architecture, Back-End Development, HTTP Requests, Express.js, Git

- Developed a RESTful API using TypeScript, Express.js, and Node.js, implementing best practices for architecture and HTTP requests.
- Developed familiarity with HTTP requests to handle calls to the API efficiently and prevent potential errors.
- Implement API documentation to enhance clarity & convenience to correctly navigate and use the API.

Website Design & Development - HTML, SCSS/SASS, TypeScript, React-Spring, Next.js

- Designed, developed, & deployed my own website showcasing my projects and skills as a developer.
- Incorporated Google Analytics A4 to monitor and increase website traffic by 200% and steadily increase weekly page views by 15%.
- Promoted my website to various social media platforms, such as LinkedIn, Instagram, and Twitter to increase traffic and exposure among users, companies, and variou developers.

Front-End Development - HTML, SCSS/SASS, JavaScript, React, TailwindCSS, Third Party API's, Git

- Completed a series of Front-End challenges using various front-end tools & languages.
- Developed multiple front-end mock websites using design files and assets to simulate real world front-end practices.
- Adhere to specific design specifications to produce accurate applications to simulate client-side design satisfaction.
- Developed interactive and user friendly applications using React.js and SCSS/SASS that incorporated UI/UX design principles.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Logistics Specialist 09/2021 - 12/2022

Frontier Supply Chain Solutions Inc.

- Utilized software systems to track and monitor shipments.
- Communicated with commercial drivers and vendors to ensure accurate and timely delivery of goods ensuring clearance that took no longer than 2 days.
- Cleared over 200+ commercial freight deliveries crossing state borders, with an average of approximately 10 deliveries a day.

Sales Associate 11/2018 - 07/2020

Zara Inc.

- Streamlined check-out process by utilizing efficient floor maintenance techniques resulting in 50% increase in productivity amongst team members.
- Effectively increased productivity by 20% training new employees on daily store tasks and procedures.
- Delivered daily revenue consistently within budget parameters through effective shop organization & sales promotion during peak hours, amplified reach by 25%.

EDUCATION

Shoreline Community College - Shoreline, WA

Purchasing, Procurement/Acquisitions and Contracts Management 09/2021 - 01/2022

Seattle Pacific University - Seattle, WA

Department of Psychology 09/2018 - 01/2019